V.BALAMURUGAN - Jr.Cloud Engineer

- Plot no: 18 varsha garden, perumalpattu, Veppampattu, thiruvallur, 602024 chennai, Tamilnadu, india
- ≥ bala.murughhan89@gmail.com
- **Q** 9003878970

PROFILE

Having 1.5 years of experience as junior Cloud Engineer, responsible for Implementing and coordinating with different patching solutions with developers and IT staff to oversee the code releases, combining an understanding of both engineering and coding from creating and implementing systems software to analyze data and improve existing ones and reports tickets issues to lead admin team to increase productivity in the workplace.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jr.Cloud Engineer, PLCTechnologies chennai

Jun 2020 - present

Roles And Resonsibilities:

- Created secured infrastructure network using VPC with security group and subnets with public and private to the company requirements.
- configured multiple Ec2 instances with preferred Os.
- Took Ec2 volumes snapshots for routine backups and archiving.
- Utilized load balancers for Ec2 nodes.
- Created services like EBS and EFS S3 buckets according to regions for data storage based on requirements.
- Created cloud watch, Auto scaling under lead guidance.
- Worked on IAM roles and policies, security and authorization to create users and access.
- Initiated vpc Peering and Transit gateway connection to communicate among vpc.
- Incorporated Nat gateways for private ip address/subnet connections, services as per client need.
- Knowledge on migration concepts have an exposure on hypervisor tool in small scale operations.
- Worked on Devops Git creating Git repository and used basic git commands.
- worked on CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins maven tool simple scale environment.
- Worked on containerization tools like Docker by converting image to container from dockerhub.
- And have basic understading on orchestration tool Kubernets,and basic configuration tools like Ansible,terraform,and monitoring tool like nagios

ORGANISATIONS

PLC TECHNOLOGIES, Jr. Cloud Engineer

Jun 2020 – present | Chennai, India

BATS (Bangalore airport terminal services),

Mar 2015 - May 2018 | Chennai, India

Cargo Assistant

SKILLS

soft skills

*Ability to handle pressure and work along with

the team members

*Good communication to convey the exact

details of work

*Able to handle new software's and applications

 $*Have\ good\ time\ management\ and\ prioritize\ the$

given task

*Ability to adopt according to the environment

and the situation

 $*good\,in\,logical\,and\,analytics\,to\,communicate$

with the metrics

*Self motivated and good in work ethics

IT Skills

Programming Languages : Python

Operating System : Linux, Windows

Cloud : AWS cloud services

Devops : Git, Maven,

jenkins, docker.

EDUCATION

B.TECH INFORMATION TECHNOLGY,

KAMBAN ENGIEERING COLEGE (ANNA UNIV ERSITY)

May 2008 – Jun 2011 TIRUVANNAMALAI, INDIA

DIPLOMA IN ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS,

PRIYADHARSHINI COLLEGE(TECHNICAL EDUCATION CHENNAI)

Mar 2005 – 2008 VELLORE(vaniyambadi), INDIA

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth : 12.05.1989.

Nationality : Indian.

Marital status : single

Languages known: Tamil, English, Hindi

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above information given by me is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

V.BALAMURUGAN

Chennai (Thiruvallur)